Mayowa Odebode

A front-end developer dedicated to creating user-focused web solutions that make life easier and more enjoyable. With over 4 years of experience building responsive web applications and services, I specialize in crafting intuitive interfaces that solve real-world problems while delivering an engaging and seamless user experience. My mission is to build solutions that are not only functional but also delightful to use, ensuring technology becomes a tool that empowers users in their daily lives.

Contact Details:

Kigali, Rwanda (250) 784-928-922

itopaodebode@gmail.com

Portfolio:

https://mayowa-odebode.netl ify.app/

EXPERIENCE

YeleGroup, Ireland & Côte d'Ivoire

Frontend Developer (remote)

FEBRUARY 2024 - NOVEMBER 2024

- Designed & developed (Bontuteur), a web app that connects tutors to students via an online booking system.
- Designed & developed (Alpha Influencer), a web app that connects businesses with top influencers in their region.
- Mentored and managed four interns in developing (Alpha SMS) a web tool
 that sends bulk messages instantly, easily schedules, and utilizes AI to
 create messages that resonate with the target audience.
- Re-designed and developed the official website for YeleGroup.
- Designed and developed (Alpha Insight), a web platform that provides an analytical dashboard, designed to provide African entrepreneurs with accurate data and actionable insights.

SAFIRUN, Kigali, Rwanda

Junior Frontend Developer

OCTOBER 2021 - JANUARY 2024

- Designed & developed in-house analytic interfaces to track & manage orders and services on the SAFIRUN mobile application.
- Rebuilt 3-year-old SAFIRUN Website and web app version for the SAFIRUN mobile app
- Designed and implemented web applications and 3rd-party software integrations as a web team liaison for all interdepartmental and customerfacing projects.
- Designed and developed an e-charging station website & a ride-hailing service website.
- Designed and developed web platforms for All-Electric Vehicle (EV) ridehailing services.

SKILLS

HTML CSS Javascript Tailwind CSS REACT GIT/GitHub

LANGUAGES

English (Proficient), Yoruba (Fluent)

EDUCATION

Middlesex University,

London, UK. — BSc (Hons) Information Technology &Business Information Systems

GRADUATED - August 2016

PROJECT(S)

thrift.rw: a web platform where users get to sell items refurbished items. **ONGOING**

afrikohub.com: an African content stock media sharing web platform where users get access to African-themed media files.

ONGOING

WOUESSI - Digital Intelligence Company, Kigali, Rwanda.

Web Developer / WordPress Developer

JAN 2021 - MAR 2021

- Set up development environments
- Designed and implemented new features and functionality
- Establishing and guiding the website's architecture
- Ensuring high performance and availability, and managing all technical aspects of the CMS
- Helped formulate an effective, responsive design and turn it into a working theme
- Utilized a deep understanding of the WP library and other standard practices to produce great WP-based products.